<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stacy R Konkiel</title>
    <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://skonkiel.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Stacy R Konkiel</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://skonkiel.github.io/media/icon_hu52a5aca58776a3b1d7435a33538a8918_904_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Stacy R Konkiel</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis landlord dataset and dashboard</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/minneapolis-landlords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/minneapolis-landlords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/skonkiel/mpls_landlords&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Download the 2020 Minneapolis landlord dataset&lt;/a&gt;: properties owned, aliases, valuation, and more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/MinneapolisAssessorData2020-Landlords/Dashboard2?:language=en-US&amp;amp;publish=yes&amp;amp;:display_count=n&amp;amp;:origin=viz_share_link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Searchable landlord dashboard&lt;/a&gt;: Search based on owner name, alias, and address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.startribune.com/minneapolis-voter-guide-mayor-city-council-candidates-ward-2021-election-charter-amendments/600096731/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Vote yes on 3, yes on rent control for Minneapolis on November 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homeownership is increasingly out of reach for the average Minnesotan, especially in Minneapolis, where one in five single family homes is rented for profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a frustrating experience trying to buy my first home last year&amp;ndash;and disappointment in the pushback against the 2021 Minneapolis ballot question on rent control&amp;ndash;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d provide a data-driven analysis of the scale of profiteering that&amp;rsquo;s happening on the backs of the average Minneapolis renter, which is at the same time making it harder for people like me to buy a home. These things are related. The root cause is a system that takes housing, a human right, and exploits it for profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my newfound status as a property owner, I have a lot more in common with the average Minneapolis renter than I do with landlords. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m providing a dataset to other renters and advocacy groups that makes it a lot easier to find out who owns rental properties in your neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is a back of napkin analysis underpinned by a (much more valuable) public dataset of Minneapolis landlords from 2020, which I&amp;rsquo;ve put a LOT of time into cleaning and normalizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read on and then VOTE YES ON 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fighting-the-llc-problem-through-data-munging&#34;&gt;Fighting the &amp;ldquo;LLC problem&amp;rdquo; through data munging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspiration for this project comes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://findmylandlord.chicagodsa.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Find My Landlord website&lt;/a&gt;, which aims to connect Chicago landlords to the shell companies and LLCs they use to avoid liability and, in some cases, accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As that project so expertly illustrates, there&amp;rsquo;s a well known &amp;ldquo;LLC problem&amp;rdquo; among housing advocates who want to learn who owns a building. Individuals and corporations that own many buildings at once tend to protect their assets by creating different LLCs for each building they own, so if they get sued, only that building is &amp;ldquo;in danger&amp;rdquo;. They sometimes even file taxes under multiple business names in order to obsfucate the fact that they own multiple rental properties. (Read on for an example of this in action.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help local housing advocates overcome the LLC problem, I decided to do some hard-core data munging. I downloaded Assessor Parcel data for 2020 from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opendata.minneapolismn.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Minneapolis&lt;/a&gt; portal. This file lists the owners, taxpayers, value, and characteristics of all Minneapolis parcels and buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cleaned the hell out of the data and then applied some techniques* in &lt;a href=&#34;https://openrefine.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Refine&lt;/a&gt; to find common owners of residential rental properties that were registered to many different LLCs and, in some cases, family members. I also ran an analysis on the results, which I share the headline findings of below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: This data was manually reviewed and cleaned to the best of my ability. There may be mistakes and/or omissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-the-data-reveals&#34;&gt;What the data reveals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-in-five-single-family-minneapolis-homes-is-rented-for-profit&#34;&gt;One in five single family Minneapolis homes is rented for profit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the 74,689 single-family homes in Minneapolis, 13,572 are rental properties. 2,545 of these rental properties are owned by what I&amp;rsquo;ll call &amp;ldquo;corporate landlords&amp;rdquo;—those who own four or more rental properties, who make their living off of renters. These are properties that could otherwise be on the market for would-be buyers who are having &lt;a href=&#34;https://minnesota.cbslocal.com/2021/09/21/twin-cities-housing-shortage/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a hell of a time finding houses&lt;/a&gt;, especially lower-income buyers who are currently priced out of the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;minneapolis-landlords-are-hiding-their-identities-to-an-alarming-extent&#34;&gt;Minneapolis landlords are hiding their identities to an alarming extent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 852 Minneapolis landlords who have registered their properties to multiple aliases: 2,961 third-parties (typically LLCs and family members) total or 3.5 aliases per owner on average, in many cases hiding their ownership from tenants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of this trickery in action—many different LLCs registered to a single family of rental property owners:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Aliases of one family&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/aliases_hu4dc075f5b568cc03b3e35966d97b7a51_120483_3dca584a32d2122a5391524ac21b5d4b.png 400w,
               /media/aliases_hu4dc075f5b568cc03b3e35966d97b7a51_120483_e0c3930994b6e88b1b40a33f0cd42a66.png 760w,
               /media/aliases_hu4dc075f5b568cc03b3e35966d97b7a51_120483_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://skonkiel.github.io/media/aliases_hu4dc075f5b568cc03b3e35966d97b7a51_120483_3dca584a32d2122a5391524ac21b5d4b.png&#34;
               width=&#34;548&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This purposeful obsfucation &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.startribune.com/north-minneapolis-renters-wage-a-fight-with-private-equity-landlords/600062754/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;makes it difficult for tenants to hold owners accountable&lt;/a&gt;. How is this legal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;private-equity-and-local-profiteers-are-making-a-killing-on-minneapolis-renters&#34;&gt;Private equity and local profiteers are making a killing on Minneapolis renters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, Minneapolis landlords collect rent on 114,203 rental units across the city. With an average rent of $1,455, that&amp;rsquo;s a whopping $166 million exiting renters pockets each month and going to landlords, rather than one&amp;rsquo;s own mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top twenty landlords (by number of properties owned) collectively own over 1,600 rental properties in Minneapolis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Top 20 rental property owners&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/top_landlords_hud9e8ec30f200bb512ada0ff485be7933_70987_8daeeae7178873f791d4d3cb54c8f0b3.png 400w,
               /media/top_landlords_hud9e8ec30f200bb512ada0ff485be7933_70987_97d144b46c4704da4cbc1a72a33548ba.png 760w,
               /media/top_landlords_hud9e8ec30f200bb512ada0ff485be7933_70987_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://skonkiel.github.io/media/top_landlords_hud9e8ec30f200bb512ada0ff485be7933_70987_8daeeae7178873f791d4d3cb54c8f0b3.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;263&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though some of the top property owners are nonprofits like Project for Pride in Living, more often they are companies like Front Yard Residential Corporation and investment funds like Carpathain Capital Management. Not exactly the picture of &amp;ldquo;mom and pop&amp;rdquo; landlords that the industry would have you believe. Definitely not who I&amp;rsquo;d want as a landlord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-working-class-cant-build-wealth-if-minneapolis-landlords-own-all-the-property&#34;&gt;The working class can&amp;rsquo;t build wealth if Minneapolis landlords own all the property&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Home ownership is an excellent way for families to build wealth. Disparities in wealth along racial lines are often tied to similar disparities in homeownership rates, which in Minneapolis were historically caused by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.minnpost.com/metro/2019/02/with-covenants-racism-was-written-into-minneapolis-housing-the-scars-are-still-visible/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;racist redlining practices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, consider this: Minneapolis landlords own rental properties worth more than $19 billion dollars (as valued by the city&amp;rsquo;s assessor office). Imagine if some of those properties could be owned by families instead! It could go a long way towards addressing inequity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mom-and-pop-landlords-shouldnt-be-let-off-the-hook&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mom and pop&amp;rdquo; landlords shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be let off the hook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11,027 single family homes that could otherwise be owned by their residents are instead owned by so-called &amp;ldquo;mom and pop&amp;rdquo; landlords that own three or fewer properties. Only 39 of these single family homes are arguably &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; mom and pop-owned—that is, rented out by someone who also lives on the property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vote-yes-on-3---rent-control-for-minneapolis&#34;&gt;Vote Yes on 3 - Rent Control for Minneapolis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minneapolis heads to the polls next Tuesday, November 2 to decide on rent control and other important ballot questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that &lt;a href=&#34;https://jacobinmag.com/2019/11/rent-control-housing-crisis-affordability-supply&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rent control works&lt;/a&gt;. We just need voters to support the measure at the ballot box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re as frustrated as I am by the extent to which landlords are winning out over the rest of us, go vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same day voter registration is available, as is early voting. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.startribune.com/minneapolis-voter-guide-mayor-city-council-candidates-ward-2021-election-charter-amendments/600096731/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Election Links at the top of the Star Tribune&amp;rsquo;s election guide&lt;/a&gt; for info on registration, finding your polling place, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dig-into-the-data&#34;&gt;Dig into the data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve archived on Github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/skonkiel/mpls_landlords&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a derivative of the 2020 Minneapolis Assessor Parcel dataset that includes rental properties, their likely owners, and the aliases they use&lt;/a&gt;. You can download it as a spreadsheet by following &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/skonkiel/mpls_landlords/blob/master/data/final_landlords.csv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;. You can also search for owners of a particular address or alias in &lt;a href=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/MinneapolisAssessorData2020-Landlords/Dashboard2?:language=en-US&amp;amp;publish=yes&amp;amp;:display_count=n&amp;amp;:origin=viz_share_link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this dashboard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;tableauPlaceholder&#39; id=&#39;viz1635431707746&#39; style=&#39;position: relative&#39;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;#&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Dashboard 2 &#39; src=&#39;https:&amp;#47;&amp;#47;public.tableau.com&amp;#47;static&amp;#47;images&amp;#47;Mi&amp;#47;MinneapolisAssessorData2020-Landlords&amp;#47;Dashboard2&amp;#47;1_rss.png&#39; style=&#39;border: none&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;object class=&#39;tableauViz&#39;  style=&#39;display:none;&#39;&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;host_url&#39; value=&#39;https%3A%2F%2Fpublic.tableau.com%2F&#39; /&gt; &lt;param name=&#39;embed_code_version&#39; value=&#39;3&#39; /&gt; &lt;param name=&#39;site_root&#39; value=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;name&#39; value=&#39;MinneapolisAssessorData2020-Landlords&amp;#47;Dashboard2&#39; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;tabs&#39; value=&#39;no&#39; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;toolbar&#39; value=&#39;yes&#39; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;static_image&#39; value=&#39;https:&amp;#47;&amp;#47;public.tableau.com&amp;#47;static&amp;#47;images&amp;#47;Mi&amp;#47;MinneapolisAssessorData2020-Landlords&amp;#47;Dashboard2&amp;#47;1.png&#39; /&gt; &lt;param name=&#39;animate_transition&#39; value=&#39;yes&#39; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;display_static_image&#39; value=&#39;yes&#39; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;display_spinner&#39; value=&#39;yes&#39; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;display_overlay&#39; value=&#39;yes&#39; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;display_count&#39; value=&#39;yes&#39; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;language&#39; value=&#39;en-US&#39; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;filter&#39; value=&#39;publish=yes&#39; /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&gt;                    var divElement = document.getElementById(&#39;viz1635431707746&#39;);                    var vizElement = divElement.getElementsByTagName(&#39;object&#39;)[0];                    if ( divElement.offsetWidth &gt; 800 ) { vizElement.style.width=&#39;100%&#39;;vizElement.style.height=(divElement.offsetWidth*0.75)+&#39;px&#39;;} else if ( divElement.offsetWidth &gt; 500 ) { vizElement.style.width=&#39;100%&#39;;vizElement.style.height=(divElement.offsetWidth*0.75)+&#39;px&#39;;} else { vizElement.style.width=&#39;100%&#39;;vizElement.style.height=&#39;1227px&#39;;}                     var scriptElement = document.createElement(&#39;script&#39;);                    scriptElement.src = &#39;https://public.tableau.com/javascripts/api/viz_v1.js&#39;;                    vizElement.parentNode.insertBefore(scriptElement, vizElement);                &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve removed owners&#39; addresses from the dataset because doxxing is bad karma. If you need to find contact information for a specific LLC that owns a rental property in order to advocate for yourself or others, &lt;a href=&#34;OpenCorporates.com&#34;&gt;OpenCorporates&lt;/a&gt; is a great resource. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://opendata.minneapolismn.gov/datasets/assessors-parcel-data-2020/explore&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;source dataset&lt;/a&gt; also includes a wealth of information on specific properties. Use this information responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mention above, I make no promises to the accuracy of the data, though I&amp;rsquo;ve tried my best. Caveat emptor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data (as well as my analyses above) includes nonprofit owners of rental properties, as well as &amp;ldquo;mom and pop&amp;rdquo; landlords and some co-ops. Public housing has been removed from the dataset (though it&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that only a fraction of rental units (5,700) are city or county owned).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post again soon to include a link to the analysis, for those who want to check my numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Revealing my technieques publicly could help shifty landlords hide their identities better in the future. Get in touch via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@stacykonkiel.org&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re a housing advocate who wants to learn more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota Wind Power</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/project/mn-wind-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/project/mn-wind-power/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transformative power of values-enacted scholarship</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/agate-transformative-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/agate-transformative-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altmetrics: The state of the art for publication planning</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/talk/altmetrics-the-state-of-the-art-for-publication-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/talk/altmetrics-the-state-of-the-art-for-publication-planning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to identifying author gender for bibliometric analyses</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/identify-author-gender-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 21:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/identify-author-gender-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In 2018, I wrote a post for &lt;a href=&#34;https://thebibliomagician.wordpress.com/2018/06/19/a-guide-to-identifying-author-gender-for-bibliometric-analyses-by-stacy-konkiel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Bibliomagician blog&lt;/a&gt; on identifying authors&#39; genders based on name analyses, based on a lively discussion on the LIS-Bibliometrics listserv. I&amp;rsquo;m reposting the blog post here under a CC-BY license.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently on the LIS-Bibliometrics listserv, Ruth Harrison (Imperial College London) posed a question on behalf of a patron who was interested in identifying authors&#39; genders based upon names listed on ~2,000 journal articles–too large a corpus for manual analysis. The community weighed in with many good suggestions for ways to approach a large scale gender analysis for author names. We thought it would be helpful to others to share what Ruth learned (with permission from the original posters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some recommendations from LIS-Bibliometrics listserv members on the best places to find author names, APIs and software you can use to analyze gender, consultants you can hire the analysis out to, and previous approaches to analysis from other gender bibliometrics researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-find-author-names-lists&#34;&gt;Where to find author names lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://login.webofknowledge.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Web of Science&lt;/a&gt; was most recommended as being a good way to download full author names for publication lists. Programmatic access via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wokinfo.com/products_tools/products/related/webservices/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Web of Science API&lt;/a&gt; is usually available for licensing (libraries are usually the purchasers of Web of Science access for institutions, so you should contact your library to inquire as to whether API access is included in your institution&amp;rsquo;s contract).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would be remiss if we did not point out the challenges that face anyone seeking to do a study that determines a person&amp;rsquo;s gender, based on name alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New citation index &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dimensions.ai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dimensions&lt;/a&gt; also makes authors&#39; full names available for download (though only for up to 50 papers at once in the free version of the app) and via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dimensions.ai/info/search-api/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dimensions API&lt;/a&gt;, which is freely available for those doing scientometrics research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, listserv members pointed out that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scopus.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Scopus&lt;/a&gt; only makes authors&#39; first initials available both in metadata downloads for publication lists and via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.elsevier.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Scopus API&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore, it is unsuitable to use in isolation for finding author names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apis-and-software&#34;&gt;APIs and software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automated gender analysis requires a bit of programming knowledge (or at least a willingness to learn). In particular, calling APIs and parsing publication metadata are two essential programming skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gender-api.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gender API&lt;/a&gt; is a recommended service that allows you to look up the likely gender (and degree of confidence) for a particular name or list of names. For example, you could query the name &amp;ldquo;Diana&amp;rdquo; and learn that the name is classified as &amp;lsquo;female&amp;rsquo;, with a 93% accuracy rate based on a sample of 523 names. The providers offer clients for interacting with the API in PHP, Python, and several other programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.namsor.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Namsor&lt;/a&gt; is another recommended API for looking up gender based on names, and it has the added feature of looking up ethnicity, as well. The free API allows for a limited number of monthly calls; you can also pay for API access to increase your API call limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://genderchecker.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GenderChecker&lt;/a&gt; is a recommended name list that can be downloaded for less than $200 USD, then analyzed. As one listserv poster explained, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not 100 percent accurate, but works for most American/European first names, especially if you have a large dataset. Be very careful with Chinese/Japanese/Korean names; most of the time they should be neutral unless you further checked.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://genderize.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Genderize.io&lt;/a&gt; is yet another API that was not recommended by listserv members, but appears in several recent studies and reports. The Genderize database reportedly contains 216,286 distinct names across 79 countries and 89 languages. It is free to use but rate-limited to 1000 requests per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the recommended Python package &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/SexMachine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SexMachine&lt;/a&gt; allows you to look up the gender for around 40,000 names. For each name you query, you will get a response for one of the following categories: andy (androgynous), male, female, mostly_male, or mostly_female. For example, the query &amp;ldquo;Paul&amp;rdquo; would return &amp;ldquo;male&amp;rdquo;, whereas the name &amp;ldquo;Stacy&amp;rdquo; would return &amp;ldquo;mostly_female&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-gender-researchers-approaches&#34;&gt;Other gender researchers&#39; approaches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listserv members also suggested that Ruth and her patron look to existing author gender analysis studies to find methods to borrow. Two in particular–a 2013 commentary from &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;, and a more recent Elsevier report–were the most mentioned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larivière, V., Ni, C., Gingras, Y., Cronin, B., &amp;amp; Sugimoto, C. R. (2013). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doi.org/10.1038/504211a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bibliometrics: Global gender disparities in science&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;504&lt;/em&gt;(7479), 211.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(2017). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elsevier.com/connect/gender-balance-in-research-new-analytical-report-reveals-uneven-progress&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gender in the global research landscape&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; study&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nature.com/polopoly_fs/7.14227.1386700530!/suppinfoFile/504211a_s1.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;supplementary files&lt;/a&gt; include a thorough discussion of how to parse Web of Science names data for a variety of countries of origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One listserv respondent pointed out that &amp;ldquo;The Elsevier report&amp;rsquo;s methodology implies they didn&amp;rsquo;t have an easier way to [identify author gender] (&amp;ldquo;Scopus Author Profiles were combined with gender-name data from social media, applied onomastics, and Wikipedia&amp;rdquo;).&amp;rdquo; More details on the study&amp;rsquo;s methods can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elsevier.com/__data/assets/pdf_file/0008/265661/ElsevierGenderReport_final_for-web.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a report appendix&lt;/a&gt;. Particularly useful is a discussion of the various name-gender APIs suitability for multi-country analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consultants&#34;&gt;Consultants&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who want to hire out the work, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.science-metrix.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Science-Metrix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elsevier.com/solutions/analytical-services&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Elsevier Analytical Services&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digital-science.com/products/consultancy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Science Consultancy&lt;/a&gt; are all businesses that offer a variety of bibliometrics analysis services, which may include gender analysis. Contact the consultancies themselves for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenges&#34;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would be remiss if we did not point out the challenges that face anyone seeking to do a study that determines a person&amp;rsquo;s gender, based on name alone. First and foremost, there is the question of &lt;strong&gt;ethics&lt;/strong&gt;: does this kind of study rob authors of their right to be identified as a particular gender that might not match the expected gender for someone with their name?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to that issue is the problem of the &lt;strong&gt;assumption of a gender binary&lt;/strong&gt;. All studies in this area tend to identify authors as &amp;ldquo;Male&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Female&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Unisex&amp;rdquo; (as in, a name that is suitable for both men and women), and &amp;ldquo;Unknown&amp;rdquo;. How can researchers more accurately identify the gender of someone who identifies as genderqueer or agender, for example? It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem possible to do so using a simple names analysis, meaning that these kinds of studies should be approached and described with that caveat in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are technical issues related to the &lt;strong&gt;dearth of useful author metadata and regional name-gender data&lt;/strong&gt;. &amp;ldquo;What about cases where the author info only includes initials?&amp;rdquo; one listserv respondent wrote. Other respondents pointed out that many name-gender analysis tools are biased towards Western names, making it difficult to do accurate analysis on authors from other areas of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Impact and Quality of Research Data Using Altmetrics and Other Indicators</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-assessing-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-assessing-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metrics Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/project/metrics-toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/project/metrics-toolkit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-intensive approaches to finding and predicting research outcomes for New Zealand health research</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/talk/data-intensive-approaches-to-finding-and-predicting-research-outcomes-for-new-zealand-health-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/talk/data-intensive-approaches-to-finding-and-predicting-research-outcomes-for-new-zealand-health-research/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimensions: Bringing down barriers between scientometricians and data</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/herzog-dimensions-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/herzog-dimensions-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HuMetricsHSS</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/project/humetricshss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/project/humetricshss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with the Dimensions and Altmetric APIs to search, visualize, and integrate research information across library systems</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/talk/working-with-the-dimensions-and-altmetric-apis-to-search-visualize-and-integrate-research-information-across-library-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/talk/working-with-the-dimensions-and-altmetric-apis-to-search-visualize-and-integrate-research-information-across-library-systems/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://owchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/media/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/discussions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring knowledge mobilization for Nordic research using patent and policy indicators</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/talk/measuring-knowledge-mobilization-for-nordic-research-using-patent-and-policy-indicators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/talk/measuring-knowledge-mobilization-for-nordic-research-using-patent-and-policy-indicators/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approaches to creating ‘humane’ research evaluation metrics for the humanities</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-approaches-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-approaches-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metrics Toolkit: an online evidence-based resource for navigating the research metrics landscape</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/champieux-metrics-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/champieux-metrics-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New article: “Scholarly Communication Librarians’ Relationship with Research Impact Indicators: An Analysis of a National Survey of Academic Librarians in the United States”</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/librarians-and-research-metrics-sutton-miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 21:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/librarians-and-research-metrics-sutton-miles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1680&#34; src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/stacykonkiel.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Screenshot-2018-07-17-16.26.18.png?resize=640%2C434&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;434&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/stacykonkiel.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Screenshot-2018-07-17-16.26.18.png?w=754 754w, https://i0.wp.com/stacykonkiel.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Screenshot-2018-07-17-16.26.18.png?resize=300%2C203 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stacykonkiel.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Screenshot-2018-07-17-16.26.18.png?resize=398%2C270 398w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Journal of Librarianship and Scholarly Communication&lt;/em&gt; just published “&lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.7710/2162-3309.2212&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Scholarly Communication Librarians’ Relationship with Research Impact Indicators: An Analysis of a National Survey of Academic Librarians in the United States&lt;/a&gt;“.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the final publication related a topic I’ve been working on since 2013 (!), when I first realized that although academic librarians were interested in research metrics, no one had yet studied the reality of how they were using these kinds of indicators in their day-to-day jobs and in support of their own careers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I’ve been privileged to work with Sarah Sutton and Rachel Miles (and for a short period, Michael Levine-Clark) on a series of publications and presentations that include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/0361526X.2017.1297593&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;“Is What’s “Trending” What’s Worth Purchasing? Insights from a National Study of Collection Development Librarians”&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Serials Librarian&lt;/em&gt; (which we also &lt;a href=&#34;http://krex.k-state.edu/dspace/handle/2097/34607&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;presented upon at NASIG 2016&lt;/a&gt; in Albuquerque)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.3138/jelis.59.1-2.05&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;“Awareness of Altmetrics among LIS Scholars and Faculty”&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Education for Library and Information Science&lt;/em&gt; (which we &lt;a href=&#34;http://krex.k-state.edu/dspace/handle/2097/34608&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;compared to librarians at ER&amp;amp;L 2016&lt;/a&gt; in Austin, TX)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;http://krex.k-state.edu/dspace/handle/2097/34459&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;What’s used to gauge when engaging?: Determining academic librarian roles in research assessment reporting services&lt;/a&gt;“, presented at the 2016 Bibliometrics and Research Assessment Symposium in Bethesda, MD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;http://krex.k-state.edu/dspace/handle/2097/34606&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Scholarly Communication Librarians’ Relationship with Research Impact Metrics&lt;/a&gt;,” a panel presentation at ‘Finding Meaning in Metrics’ at ALA Annual 2016 in Orlando, FL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Use of Altmetrics in US-based academic libraries,” a presentation at the Second Altmetrics Conference in Amsterdam (summarized on &lt;a href=&#34;https://altmetricsconf.wordpress.com/2015/10/12/altmetrics-in-the-library-session/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the Altmetrics Conference blog&lt;/a&gt; by Ian Mulvaney)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;http://altmetrics.org/altmetrics15/konkiel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Myth vs. reality: Altmetrics and librarians,&lt;/a&gt;” a presentation at the Altmetrics15 workshop in Amsterdam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ultimately learned that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your seniority/years of experience has no effect upon how familiar you are likely to be with various research metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Librarians and LIS educators alike are more familiar with traditional research impact metrics like the JIF than they are with altmetrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Altmetrics are least likely to be used for collection development, though this is a use case I’ve been promoting for a long time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more scholcomm-related duties you have in your job, the more you’ll use metrics of all kinds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Altmetric is the most popular altmetrics database used by librarians 😎&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah and Rachel plan to carry this path of research forward, expanding the scope of the study to include librarians worldwide, and also possibly looking at library promotion and tenure documents’ discussion of metrics. I wish them the very best and want to once again express my gratitude towards them as collaborators: Ladies, I hope to work with you both again in the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awareness of Altmetrics among LIS Scholars and Faculty</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/sutton-awareness-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/sutton-awareness-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altmetrics: “big data” that map the influence of New Zealand research</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-altmetrics-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-altmetrics-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and Sustaining a Grassroots Library Organization: A Three-Year Retrospective of Library Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/finnell-building-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/finnell-building-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mellon Grant to Support Values-Based Metrics for the Humanities and Social Sciences</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/mellon-humetrics-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 16:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/mellon-humetrics-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-1494 aligncenter&#34; src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/stacykonkiel.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/humetrics.png?resize=323%2C427&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;323&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/stacykonkiel.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/humetrics.png?resize=226%2C300 226w, https://i1.wp.com/stacykonkiel.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/humetrics.png?zoom=2&amp;resize=323%2C427 646w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 323px) 100vw, 323px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  CC-BY Nicky Agate / Medium
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to announce that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://humetricshss.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HuMetricsHSS&lt;/a&gt; research team–which &lt;a href=&#34;https://trianglesci.org/2016/05/31/humetrics-building-humane-metrics-for-the-humanities/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;I was a part of at the 2016 TriangleSCI conference&lt;/a&gt;–has received the support of the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation to continue our work of encouraging the discovery and use of “humane” research evaluation metrics for the humanities and social sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HSS scholars are increasingly frustrated by the prevalence of the use of evaluation metrics (borrowed from the sciences) that do not accurately capture the impacts of their work. Our grand vision is to develop better metrics, ones that are rooted in the values that are important to scholars. This grant-funded research is a start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cal.msu.edu/news/humetricshss&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the press release&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are reverse-engineering the way metrics have operated in higher education,” said Christopher P. Long, Dean of the College of Arts &amp;amp; Letters at Michigan State University and one of the Principal Investigators (PIs) of the Mellon-funded project. “We begin not with what can be measured technologically, but by listening to scholars themselves as they identify the practices of scholarship that enrich their work and connect it to a broader public.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;We’ll be sharing updates on the HuMetricsHSS project from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://humetricshss.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;our website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/humetricshss&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;, so please follow along!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much gratitude to the Mellon Foundation for supporting HuMetricsHSS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I just deleted my ten-year Twitter history</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/deleted-twitter-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 21:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/deleted-twitter-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just used a service called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gocardigan.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cardigan&lt;/a&gt; to delete the 10k+ tweets I’ve published since 2007, when I first joined Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but I’ve changed a lot since I was 24 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn’t make sense to me to keep ten years worth of miscellany–silly jokes, uninformed hot takes, occasional sharp insights, and so on–up on the Internet, gathering dust, making advertising money for Twitter. I don’t want to support a company that even with a $10.8 billion valuation somehow can’t get it right and stop &lt;a href=&#34;http://forward.com/fast-forward/374276/antifas-most-prominent-jew-booted-from-twitter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;banning innocent users rather than the Nazis who are harrassing them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t enjoy Twitter anymore. Over the years, Twitter has gone from a great place (to stay in touch with friends and former colleagues worldwide, to find interesting research and industry news, to meet new people) to one that seriously bums me out every time I log on (every day brings a new outrage, smart people sniping at each other, Mean Librarian Twitter, and unintelligible memes). It’s become superficial on a lot of levels. It’s often used as a tool to demean and call out rather than enrich and uplift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said, I’m not going to delete my account outright. Twitter is still somewhat important professionally, so I’ll continue using it to share the occasional piece of research or to livetweet interesting conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I’d rather let my writing and research speak for itself, in longform. And for my personal and professional relationships to deepen, offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be slowly unfollowing accounts who aren’t directly relevant to my interests or my work at Altmetric (sorry!) and hopefully logging on a lot less. I’ll also aim to delete my tweets and favorites every so often, to keep things fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need me, email me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@stacykonkiel.org&#34;&gt;hello@stacykonkiel.org&lt;/a&gt; (personal) or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:stacy@altmetric.com&#34;&gt;stacy@altmetric.com&lt;/a&gt; (work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With love and gratitude to my friends and followers for ten years of shitposting and networking…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;xx&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is What’s “Trending” What’s Worth Purchasing? Insights from a National Study of Collection Development Librarians</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/sutton-is-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/sutton-is-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library Pipeline launches “Innovation in Libraries” micro-grant</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/innovation-micro-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 16:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/innovation-micro-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m super excited to announce that the Innovation in Libraries grant is now accepting applications: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.awesomefoundation.org/en/chapters/libraries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.awesomefoundation.org/en/chapters/libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A core group of Library Pipeliners has been working hard for months to recruit rank-and-file librarians worldwide, many of whom are funding this grant out of their own pockets (!). Each month through August 2017, our Awesome Foundation chapter will award a $1000 USD grant to prototype library-based innovations (both technical and non-technical in nature) that are inclusive, daring, and diverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so proud of this grassroots effort to support risk-taking in librarianship. This is a great step towards building community through organizing, and I’m really excited to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special recognition goes to Josh Finnell (Los Alamos National Lab), Robin Champieux (OHSU), and Bonnie Tijerina (Data &amp;amp; Society/ER&amp;amp;L), all of whom were crucial to getting this project off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the grant, please do visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.librarypipeline.org/innovation/innovation-microfunding/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;grant webpage&lt;/a&gt; or apply via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.awesomefoundation.org/en/chapters/libraries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Awesome Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Altmetric Scores in the Parkinson’s Disease Literature</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/araujo-top-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/araujo-top-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altmetrics and the reform of the promotion &amp; tenure system</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/altmetrics-promotion-tenure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 22:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/altmetrics-promotion-tenure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past few weeks, I’ve been working with a colleague at Altmetric to develop a guide for using altmetrics in one’s promotion and tenure dossier. (Keep an eye out for the resulting blog post and handout on Altmetric.com–I think they’re going to be good!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Altmetrics and P&amp;amp;T is a topic that’s come up a lot recently, and predictably the responses are usually one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you seriously want to give people tenure based on their number of Twitter followers?!!?! ::rageface::&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hmm, that’s a pretty interesting idea! If applied correctly (i.e. in tandem with expert peer review and traditional metrics like citation counts, etc), I could see how altmetrics could improve the evaluation process for P&amp;amp;T.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can probably guess how I lean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I wanted to think aloud about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.insidehighered.com/advice/2014/01/13/essay-calls-reform-tenure-and-promotion-system&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;an editorial I recently read in &lt;em&gt;Inside Higher Ed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (a bit late to the game–the essay was written in 2014). It’s a great summary of many of the issues that plague P&amp;amp;T here in the States, and in particular the bits about “legitimacy markers” make a great argument in favor of recognizing altmetrics in P&amp;amp;T evaluation and preparation guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, I’ve excerpted the parts [to which I want to respond] (and the &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;bits I want to emphasize&lt;/span&gt;), but &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.insidehighered.com/advice/2014/01/13/essay-calls-reform-tenure-and-promotion-system&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;please visit &lt;em&gt;Inside Higher Ed&lt;/em&gt; and read the piece in its entirety&lt;/a&gt;, it’s worth your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The assumption that we know a scholar’s work is excellent if it has been recognized by a very narrow set of legitimacy markers adds bias to the process and works against recognition of newer form of scholarship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;[&amp;#8230;]&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Typically candidates for tenure and promotion submit a personal narrative describing their research, a description of the circulation, acceptance rate and impact factors of the journals or press where they published, a count and list of their citations, and material on external grants.  &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;This model of demonstration of impact favors certain disciplines over others, disciplinary as opposed to interdisciplinary work, and scholarship whose main purpose is to add to academic knowledge.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/em&gt;[Emphasis mine.]
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;In my view, the problem is not that using citation counts and journal impact factors is “a” way to document the quantity and quality of one’s scholarship. &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;The problem is that it has been normalized as the only way.&lt;/span&gt; All other efforts to document scholarship and contributions &amp;#8212; whether they be for interdisciplinary work, work using critical race theory or feminist theory, qualitative analysis, digital media or policy analysis are then suspect, marginalized, and less than.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;Using the prestige of academic book presses, citation counts and federal research awards to judge the quality of scholarship whose purpose is to directly engage with communities and public problems misses the point.&lt;/span&gt; Interdisciplinary and engaged work on health equity should be measured by its ability to affect how doctors act and think.&lt;/em&gt; [One might argue that altmetrics like citations in public policy documents and clinical care guidelines are a good proxy for this.] &lt;em&gt;Research on affirmative action in college admissions should begin to shape admissions policies.&lt;/em&gt; [Perhaps such evidence could be sourced from press releases and mainstream media coverage of said changes in admissions policies.]&lt;em&gt; One may find key theoretical and research pieces in these areas published in top tier journals and cited in the Web of Science, but they should also find them in policy reports cited at NIH&lt;/em&gt; [again, citations in policy docs useful here],&lt;em&gt; or used by a local hospital board to reform doctor training&lt;/em&gt; [mining training handbooks and relevant websites could help locate such evidence].&lt;em&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;We should not be afraid to look for impact of scholarship there, or give that evidence credibility.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Work that is addressing contemporary social problems deserves to be evaluated by criteria better suited to its purposes and not relegated to the back seat behind basic or traditional scholarship.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Altmetrics technologies aren’t yet advanced enough to do most of the things I’ve suggested above (in particular, to mine news coverage or the larger Web for mentions of the effects of research, rather than links to research articles themselves). But the field is very young, and I expect we’ll get there soon enough. And in the meantime, we’ve got some pretty decent proxies for true impact already in the main altmetrics services (i.e. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.altmetric.com/blog/new-source-alert-policy-documents/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;policy citations in Altmetric Explorer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://plumanalytics.com/citations-arent-telling/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;clinical citations in PlumX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.impactstory.org/introducing-depsy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dependency PageRank for useful software projects in Depsy/Impactstory&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the shorter term, we need for academics to advocate for the inclusion of altmetrics in promotion &amp;amp; tenure evaluation and preparation guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most researchers don’t know that this data is available, so they tend not to use it in preparing their dossiers. Fair enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What concerns me are the researchers who are aware of altmetrics, but who are hesitant to include it in their dossiers for fear that their colleagues a) won’t know what to do with the data, or b) won’t take them seriously if they include it. After all, there’s a lot of misinformation out there about what altmetrics are meant to do, and if you’ve got a reviewer that’s misinformed or that has a bone to pick re: altmetrics, that could potentially affect your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the tenure committees, often made up of reviewers from all disciplines and at all (post-tenure) stages of their career. If they’re presented with altmetrics as evidence in a P&amp;amp;T dossier but a) they’re biased against altmetrics, and/or b) their university’s review guidelines don’t confirm that altmetrics–in the service of providing evidence for specific claims to impact–are a respectable form of evidence for one’s dossier, then the tenure applicant is either met with confusion or skepticism (at best) or responded to with outright hostility (at worst).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Before you think I’m being melodramatic re: “outright hostility”–you should see some of the anti-altmetrics diatribes out there. As in many other aspects of life, some people aren’t content with the “you do it your way, I’ll do it my way” thing–they are &lt;em&gt;pissed&lt;/em&gt; that you dare to challenge the status quo and will attack those who suggest differently.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone reading this post that’s got a modicum of influence at their university (i.e. you’ve got tenure status and/or voting rights on your university’s faculty council) should go and petition their vice provost of faculty affairs to update their university-wide P&amp;amp;T review and preparation guidelines to include altmetrics. Or, at the very least, focus on changing departmental/college P&amp;amp;T guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve done so, we’re that much closer to reforming the P&amp;amp;T process to respect the good work that’s being done by &lt;em&gt;all academics&lt;/em&gt;, not just those who meet a very traditional set of criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altmetrics: diversifying the understanding of influential scholarship</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-altmetrics-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-altmetrics-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“The Use of Altmetrics in Promotion and Tenure” published in Educause Review</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/altmetrics-in-promotion-tenure-educause-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 01:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/altmetrics-in-promotion-tenure-educause-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://er.educause.edu/articles/2016/3/the-use-of-altmetrics-in-promotion-and-tenure&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; I co-authored along with Cassidy Sugimoto (Indiana University) and Sierra Williams (LSE Impact Blog) was recently published in the &lt;em&gt;Educause Review&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the intro: “Promotion and tenure decisions in the United States often rely on various scientometric indicators (e.g., citation counts and journal impact factors) as a proxy for research quality and impact. Now a new class of metrics — altmetrics — can help faculty provide impact evidence that citation-based metrics might miss: for example, the influence of research on public policy or culture, the introduction of lifesaving health interventions, and contributions to innovation and commercialization. But to do that, college and university faculty and administrators alike must take more nuanced, responsible, and informed approaches to using metrics for promotion and tenure decisions”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://er.educause.edu/articles/2016/3/the-use-of-altmetrics-in-promotion-and-tenure&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the full article on the &lt;em&gt;Educause Review&lt;/em&gt; website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit AMA – May 10th!</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/reddit-ama-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 16:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/reddit-ama-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;section class=&#34;article-content&#34;&gt;_[&lt;span class=&#34;blog-meta-date&#34;&gt;Cross-posted from the Digital Science blog on 25th April 2016 &lt;/span&gt;][1]_&lt;/section&gt; &lt;section class=&#34;article-content&#34;&gt; 
&lt;div class=&#34;article-body&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-18128 aligncenter&#34; src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/www.digital-science.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/reddit-logo.jpg?resize=350%2C117&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px&#34; srcset=&#34;https://www.digital-science.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/reddit-logo-300x100.jpg 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.digital-science.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/reddit-logo.jpg?resize=350%2C117&amp;#038;ssl=1 350w&#34; alt=&#34;reddit logo&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; height=&#34;117&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Join us for a Reddit Ask Me Anything with Stacy Konkiel (&lt;a class=&#34;ProfileHeaderCard-screennameLink u-linkComplex js-nav&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/skonkiel&#34;&gt;@&lt;span class=&#34;u-linkComplex-target&#34;&gt;skonkiel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), Outreach &amp; Engagement Manager at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.altmetric.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Altmetric&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;at 6pm GMT/1pm EDT on the 10th May.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    The Reddit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/iama/&#34;&gt;Ask Me Anything&lt;/a&gt; forum is a great way to engage and interact with subject experts in a direct and honest Q&amp;A, asking those burning questions you’ve always wanted to get their perspective on! Mark Hahnel, the founder of &lt;a href=&#34;https://figshare.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Figshare&lt;/a&gt;, Euan Adie, the founder of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.altmetric.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Altmetric&lt;/a&gt; and John Hammersley, co-founder of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.overleaf.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Overleaf&lt;/a&gt;, have also all participated in this popular discussion forum.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Following their lead, on Tuesday 10th May at 6pm UK time / 1pm EST Stacy Konkiel, Altmetric’s Outreach &amp; Engagement Manager, will be taking part in an AMA on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AskScience subreddit&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-18203 aligncenter&#34; src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/www.digital-science.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Photo-on-4-22-16-at-4.53-PM-2-1024x683.jpg?resize=600%2C400&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&#34; srcset=&#34;https://www.digital-science.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Photo-on-4-22-16-at-4.53-PM-2-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.digital-science.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Photo-on-4-22-16-at-4.53-PM-2-768x512.jpg 768w, https://i1.wp.com/www.digital-science.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Photo-on-4-22-16-at-4.53-PM-2-1024x683.jpg?resize=600%2C400&amp;#038;ssl=1 1024w, https://www.digital-science.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Photo-on-4-22-16-at-4.53-PM-2.jpg 1080w&#34; alt=&#34;Photo on 4-22-16 at 4.53 PM #2&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Stacy plans to talk about what the metrics and indicators we like to rely upon in science (impact factor, altmetrics, citation counts, etc) to understand “broader impact” and “intellectual merit,” are actually measuring what we purport they measure.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    She is not sure they do! And instead thinks that right now, we’re just using rough proxies to understand influence and attention. We’re in danger of abusing the metrics that are supposed to save us all, altmetrics, just like science has done with the journal impact factor.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Stacy will talk about improving measures of research impact, but is also open to taking other relevant questions.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    If you wish to participate in the Ask Me Anything, you will need to &lt;a title=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/register&#34; href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;register with Reddit.&lt;/a&gt; There will also be some live tweeting from &lt;a class=&#34;ProfileHeaderCard-screennameLink u-linkComplex js-nav&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/altmetric&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@&lt;span class=&#34;u-linkComplex-target&#34;&gt;altmetric&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;ProfileHeaderCard-screennameLink u-linkComplex js-nav&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/digitalsci&#34;&gt;@&lt;span class=&#34;u-linkComplex-target&#34;&gt;digitalsci&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and questions on the #AskStacyAltmetric hashtag, so keep your eyes peeled!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results of the #Force2016 Innovation Challenge: we won!</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/force2016-innovation-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 14:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/force2016-innovation-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to report that along with the team behind &lt;a href=&#34;https://elevator.jisc.ac.uk/e/force2016/idea/radian&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Radian&lt;/a&gt; (a knowledge portal for data management librarians), the &lt;a href=&#34;https://elevator.jisc.ac.uk/e/force2016/idea/metric-toolkit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Metric Tookit&lt;/a&gt; (pitched by me, &lt;a href=&#34;https://coateshl.wordpress.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Heather Coates&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7023-9832&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Champieux&lt;/a&gt;) has won the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.force11.org/meetings/force2016/program/agenda/session-pitch-it-innovation-challenge&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Force 2016 PitchIt Innovation Challenge&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hugely proud and very excited about bringing this idea to life. In talking with researchers and librarians worldwide over the past two years, the single biggest request I tend to get is an easy way to understand what metrics &lt;em&gt;really mean&lt;/em&gt; (or more importantly, what they &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; mean). This toolkit will be that resource.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve already started to get some promising feedback about our plans, including these nice tweets from (one of my favorite open scientists :)) Erin McKiernan and Sara Mannheimer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
    Agreed, think this is a very cool idea! &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/force2016?src=hash&#34;&gt;#force2016&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/innovationchallenge?src=hash&#34;&gt;#innovationchallenge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/metrics?src=hash&#34;&gt;#metrics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/yAI5UAi4BO&#34;&gt;https://t.co/yAI5UAi4BO&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    — Erin McKiernⓐn (@emckiernan13) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/emckiernan13/status/722531777084989441&#34;&gt;April 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about our vision, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://elevator.jisc.ac.uk/e/force2016/idea/metric-toolkit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jisc Elevator site&lt;/a&gt;, where we’ve submitted our pitch and an accompanying video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to Heather and Robin, who were the driving force behind developing such a compelling pitch deck! And thank you also to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.force11.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Force11&lt;/a&gt; community–we look forward to sharing our results with you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The use of Altmetrics in promotion and tenure</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-use-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-use-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case against (only) using metrics for collection management</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/metrics-collection-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 15:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/metrics-collection-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m currently working with Sarah Sutton at Emporia State University on launching a survey to get a sense of how librarians use altmetrics, including for collection development purposes. (Is it useful to know if a book has been cited in a policy document, even if it’s rarely circulated, so you don’t deaccession it? Can monitoring online activity for all scholarship–even articles that a library doesn’t have subscription access to–help librarians make much quicker purchasing decisions for articles and journals that patrons might request? And so on.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it was with a lot of interest that I read Chris Bourg’s “&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisbourg.wordpress.com/2015/07/12/infrastructure-and-culture-a-job-talk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Infrastructure and Culture: A job talk&lt;/a&gt;” yesterday. In the talk (which rightly landed her the position of Director of MIT Libraries, at least in part), Bourg describes how institutional cultures are so important to (among other things) the failure or success of campus scholarly communication initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crucially, she talks about the unintended consequences that a culture of quantification can have upon decisions that are made for library collections, especially collections that might not be popular but that might inform important research projects, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.stanford.edu/news/2014/june/evolution-language-brazil-060414.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this study that uses old, uncirculated volumes to study the evolution of Brazilian Portuguese over time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisbourg.wordpress.com/2015/07/12/infrastructure-and-culture-a-job-talk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;read Bourg’s post in its entirety&lt;/a&gt;, but wanted to pull out one section in particular that I think is a valuable way to think about assessment and metrics w/r/t library services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left:30px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Developing new ways of demonstrating the impact of our services and collections is a way of promoting a culture that values assessment, but also recognizes that the true impact of libraries and librarians is often delayed and too idiosyncratic to show up in most of the standard ROI style assessment tools currently in use.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left:30px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;So while I am a fan of assessment and data-driven decision-making, I think it is critically important that we make sure the data we are using captures the full story of our impact. As a social scientist with experience teaching and consulting on statistics and research methods, I’m committed to making sure that the assessment tools we use in libraries are the right ones, that the data we collect measures what really matters, and that we use methods appropriate to the decisions we want to make.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this spirit, I ask: what methods are you using to drive collection development at your library? And how might you use metrics (including altmetrics) in a more nuanced way to achieve goals that are in line with your larger library (and institutional) culture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS Keep your eyes on your inbox–if you’re a librarian at an R1 institution in the US, I’ll likely be emailing you soon to ask you to participate in our survey on altmetrics and libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We’re overdue on altmetrics for the digital humanities</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/were-overdue-on-altmetrics-for-the-digital-humanities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/were-overdue-on-altmetrics-for-the-digital-humanities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humanities researchers I’ve talked to usually fall into one of two camps when it comes to altmetrics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Altmetrics are amazing! I’ve been looking for a better way to understand the use and impacts of my work.” or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“This is just another tool that favors the sciences and tries to reduce the complexities of my research into a single formula. It will never work for me.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an altmetrics advocate and humanist by training, I unsurprisingly tend to fall into the first camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing a lot of reading and thinking lately on how research is evaluated in the humanities, and it seems to sadly be as an opaque of a process as in the sciences. By and large, you’re judged by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the university press you’ve published your book(s) with,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reviews that other scholars write about your books, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;occasionally, by the citations your journal articles and books receive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, this framework tends to favors books and, to a lesser extent, journal articles. The value of digital scholarship projects (websites, interactive exhibitions, etc), software, and research data aren’t taken into account under this model. Thank goodness that’s starting to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past few years, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mla.org/guidelines_evaluation_digital&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;scholarly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://historians.org/teaching-and-learning/current-projects/committee-on-professional-evaluation-of-digital-scholarship-in-history/aha-draft-guidelines-for-evaluation-of-digital-scholarship&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;societies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.academiccommons.org/2014/07/24/digital-scholarship-and-the-tenure-and-promotion-process/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;some universities&lt;/a&gt; have created guidelines to help traditionalists understand the impacts of digital scholarship projects. Faculty are encouraged to think beyond the monograph when considering what types of work might have a lasting influence on the profession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these guidelines tend not to address newer types of quantitative and qualitative data, sourced from the web, that can help reviewers understand the full scope of the impacts your work may have. This data can include newer impact metrics like numbers of website visitors, what other scholars are saying about your work on their research blogs and social media, how many members of the public have reviewed your books on GoodReads and Amazon, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s where my current work comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/i.imgur.com/48bR0YU.png?w=640&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m now in the process of talking with humanities researchers, from department chairs to graduate students, to better understand what types of data might be useful in supplementing their understanding of impacts for digital humanities research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I’ve done two talks in the past week–&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1393376&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ischoolgroups.sjsu.edu/asistsc/sig-symposium/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ASIS&amp;amp;T Virtual Symposium on Information Technology in the Arts &amp;amp; Humanities&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1394962&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;commons.pacificu.edu/arcs/program.html&#34;&gt;Advancing Research Communication &amp;amp; Scholarship&lt;/a&gt; meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both talks were intended to get conversations started about altmetrics and the humanities–what might work, what would never work, what data sources could potentially be tracked that aren’t yet included in services like Altmetric and PlumX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be doing more researching, writing, thinking and speaking on the topic in the coming months–stay tuned for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I’d love to get your feedback in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperative for Open Altmetrics</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-imperative-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-imperative-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 30-Day Impact Challenge: the ultimate guide to raising the profile of your research</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-30-day-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-30-day-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New opportunities for repositories in the age of altmetrics</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-new-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-new-2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altmetrics a 21 st-century solution to determining research quality</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-altmetrics-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-altmetrics-2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking citations and altmetrics for research data: Challenges and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-tracking-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/publication/konkiel-tracking-2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://skonkiel.github.io/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skonkiel.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
